(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T08:32:19.733276",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みんなー！
Everyone!
みえているのかなー？
Can you see me?
みえるー？
Can you see?
みんな、今日は来てくれてありがとうなのら！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming today, nanora!
なんと今日はホロライブ4期生姫森ルーナのなのら！
Today is Hololive 4th Gen Himemori Luna's...
誕生日なのらー！やったのらー！おー！
birthday, nanora! Yay, nanora! Woo!
ちょっと、ルーナ最初から走るとやばいからちょっと静かにやろうと思うんだよね。
Running right from the start might be intense,
so I thought I'd do it quietly.
みんな、この、左腕はなのら、今までのルーナ誕生祭、走るたぐって
Everyone, this left arm, nanora,
for all of Luna's birthday festivals, running...
ずっとして走るのらよ！あ、ルーナの腕まだ切断はしてないのら！そのままなのら！
I've always run! Ah, Luna's arm hasn't been amputated yet! It's still there!
今日はね、もう、あの、前回のように事故ったりしない感じでやっていく予定なので、みんな安心いてほしいのら！
Today, unlike last time, I plan to do it
without any accidents, so please rest assured!
ありがと、なんと、なのら！今日10月10日で
Thank you! Surprisingly, nanora!
Today, October 10th,
0歳になったのらー！やったのらー！
I turned 0 years old, nanora! Yay, nanora!
0歳おめでとう！あ、ありがとーなのらー！
Happy 0th birthday! Ah, thank you, nanora!
まだ使ってないのだよ。
I haven't used it yet, you know.
0歳なのらみんな！みんなおめでとうって言って走るのら！0歳おめでとう！
I'm 0 years old, everyone! Everyone say
congratulations and run! Happy 0th birthday!
まあ、誕生日ということでね、まあみんな、誕生日と言ったら、
Well, since it's my birthday, you know,
when you say birthday,
やっぱあれなのだよね。誕生日、ケーキ！ということでね、ケーキを食べるの、食べていこうと思うんだけどー
It's definitely that thing, right? Birthday, cake!
So, I'm thinking of eating some cake, but—
羊！羊？
Sheep! Sheep?
羊ケーキよ！ルーナケーキ食べたのだけどー
Sheep cake! I ate Luna cake, but—
おおー！ケーキなのらー！
Whoa! A cake, nanora!
ケーキなのらー！ふう…
A cake, nanora! Whew...
ケーキ！みんな聞いてなのら！このケーキでっかいケーキがルーナのために、羊が持ってきたくれたの！
Cake! Everyone listen, nanora! This huge cake,
Sheep brought it for Luna!
あ、息切れしてないのら！
Ah, I'm not out of breath, nanora!
これ演技！これ演技なのら！だから、なんで息切れなんかしらんの！みんな見てなのら！
This is acting! This is acting, nanora!
So why would I be out of breath! Everyone look!
しょぐま…しょうがもっと作って…みんな聞いてなのら、ルーナこのね、誕生日ケーキ、でっかい誕生日ケーキ！
Shoguma... Shogama made more... Everyone listen, nanora, Luna is eating this birthday cake, this huge birthday cake!
あっ、あ、火がついてる！火がついてるからじゃ、まず…
Ah, ah, the fire is lit! Since the fire is lit, first...
息切れしないのらよ！はっぴばーすでい、るーな！
I'm not out of breath, nanora!
Happy birthday, Luna!
はっぴばーすでい、るーな！はっぴばーすでい、るーな！はっぴばーすでい、るーな！
わーい！はあ…はあ…
Yay! Haah... haah...
みんな、ありがとー！0歳になったの！
Everyone, thank you! I turned 0 years old!
おっきいと…おっきいと…ろうそく消えた！
Big... big... the candle went out!
お祝いはありがとう！じゃあケーキ早速食べたいと思うのらよ！いれよ！
Thank you for the celebration! Well then,
I'd like to eat the cake right away! Put it in!
フォーク！たきーす！
Fork! Takis!
これからね、すずの作ったケーキをじっしょくにいこうと思うのら。
Now then, I'm thinking of tasting the cake Suzu made.
ケーキ…ニュート…ちょきん？
Cake... Newt... Savings?
あ、みんな、ケーキ！
Ah, everyone, cake!
ちょっと動かないで、リーノな。ケーキなのだ！
Don't move, Riino! It's cake!
食べるのだ！もぐもぐもぐ…もぐもぐ、うめぇ！
Eat it! Munch munch munch... munch munch, delicious!
うめえのら。おめえケーキもっとお替わりするのら、おいすぃー！
It's delicious! You, have more seconds of cake, delicious!
おいすい。あ、おいしめぇなケーキ、おいし。あんもあんも、あんもあんも！
Delicious. Ah, delicious cake, delicious. Nom nom, nom nom!
うめえのら。
It's delicious.
お疲れってねえのらよ。なのこなんで連日疲れないのらよ。
You're not tired at all. Nano-ko, why are you never tired?
あ、待つなのだ！まだルーナ全部食べてないのらよ、ケーキ。
Ah, wait! Luna hasn't finished eating all the cake yet.
な、なんだんで、なんでなのだ。
W-why, why is that?
あ、そういえば！なんとね、みんな聞いてほしいのら！
Ah, by the way! Guess what, everyone, I want you to listen!
なんと先輩たちからね、お祝いメッセージの代わりに、あのものをね、もらっているのら！
You know what, we got celebratory messages from the senpais instead, we received that thing!
そのコーナーに行くのら！
We're going to that corner!
なんと！そのコーナーは…ジェスチャーゲーム！
And that corner is... Gesture Game!
先輩たちからもらったのは、なんとどうやらジェスチャーゲームのお題みたいなのね。
What we got from the senpais apparently seems to be prompts for a gesture game.
これをうまくね、みんなにね、伝えることができれば、ケーキの続きを食べていいってことになったのらよ。
If I can successfully convey this to everyone, I get to keep eating the rest of the cake.
全部で8問、8問、8問、8問！8問あるから、そのうちゴモの正解がクリアの条件らしいのら。
There are 8 questions in total—8, 8, 8! Since there are 8 questions, getting 5 right seems to be the clear condition.
きつくでえなら、頑張るのらみんな！当ててほしいのらよろしくなのだ。
If that's tough, do your best everyone! I want you to guess right, please.
じゃあ、まず最初の、お題は、どなたからなのかな？
Well then, first up, whose prompt is this?
え！？なんと！すばるちゃ先輩からのお題なのだ！
Eh!? What! It's a prompt from Subaru-cha senpai!
簡単そうなのだね！すばるちゃ先輩なら、ちょろちょろっとさらっと、やっちゃうわよみんな当ててんなのだね！
Sounds easy! Being Subaru-cha senpai, I'll breeze right through it, everyone guess it, okay!
聞いてるのよ？
Are you listening?
えーっと、じゃ、えーと
Um, well, um...
あ、当たってるほら！当たってる！痛い痛い痛いな、当たった！当たった！
Ah, it's hitting, look! It's hitting! Ouch ouch ouch, it hit! It hit!
正解は、ゴリラ！簡単すぎたのらね！
The answer is a gorilla! That was too easy!
皆さんすごいのだら。やっぱ簡単な問題はね、みんなパパッとね1秒で片付いちゃうのらね！
Everyone is amazing. Easy questions really get solved in a second by everyone!
じゃ、次行くのらよ。次ののお題は、うーん…え？
Well then, moving on to the next. The next prompt is, hmm... eh?
なんかしゃがむのおくねえのら。きついのだけど
Somehow squatting is weird. It's tough, though
おい！これ！ちゃんと、これ、わかり、これ！ちゃんと、して！これおかしい！えっと、ええとなんだこれ！ええと
Hey! This! Properly, this, understand, this! Properly, do this! This is weird! Um, um what is this! Um...
おお、ほら！
Oh, look!
え、なんか違う！違う！あ、本当！あ、当たった？みんな当たった？当たったからな！
Eh, something's wrong! Wrong! Ah, really! Ah, did you get it? Did everyone get it? Because you got it!
正解は、鶏なのら！
The answer is a chicken!
あひるだったね、そうだね。鶏そっくりだったならでしょ。
It was a duck, wasn't it, that's right. It looked just like a chicken, right.
ま、これがね、えっと、すばるちゃ先輩からのお題をね、にもいただいたのらね！
Well, as for this, um, we also received a prompt from Subaru-cha senpai!
次は、なんと！次の先輩からのお題は
Next is, what! The prompt from the next senpai is
水飲みてえのら。
I want to drink water.
なんと！まつりじゃ先輩からのお題なのだ！ありがとなのだ！
What! It's a prompt from Matsuri-ja senpai! Thank you!
まつりじゃ先輩の
Matsuri-ja senpai's...
えーと、なんだこれ？ えーと…
Eh? What is this? Uhm...
なんだみんな？
What is it, everyone?
みんな同じような動きになって…
Everyone's making the same movements...
あってる！あってってる！
That's right! That's right!
みんなの正解なんだ！
Everyone got it right!
ゴジラ！
Godzilla!
なんのなんだろ、あってたんだね！正解なんだ、ありがとう！
What was it? You got it right! You got it right, thank you!
次まして、えー…、またまた先輩の2つなのだ、お題が。
Next up, um... another prompt from a senior.
なんだこれ？
What is this?
おい、なんだ、まさか知らねえよ。
Hey, what? No way, I don't know this.
いやいや、いいのな？
No, no, is this good?
これ…、い、痛いな！？
This... Ow, that hurts!?
痛いの正解？
Is pain the correct answer?
正解なんだろ？
That's the correct answer, right?
ブレイクダンス！
Breakdance!
なんでこんな激しいのを選んだんだろ？
Why did they choose such an intense one?
とりあえず先輩の2番目の問題なんだ、みんなありがとう！
Anyway, that was the second question from a senior, thanks everyone!
今いばんとこ全部、あ、全問正解すごいのだ！
So far all of you got them right, amazing!
ってことでまして、えー…、次の問題が…
And so, um... the next question is...
なんと、こちらの先輩からお題をいただきましたのだ！
I received a prompt from this senior over here!
あ、はい、えーと…
Ah, yes, um...
マリン船長からお題をもらいましたのだ！
I got a prompt from Marine-senchou!
えーと、マリン船長のお題1個目は、あ、なるほど。
Uhm, Marine-senchou's first prompt is, ah, I see.
これはみんなもう0.0秒で答えちゃうのだね。
Everyone's gonna answer this in 0.0 seconds.
簡単なのだよ。
It's easy, you know.
ご自身にと願いしますのだ。
Please take care of yourself.
あ、いたいた！、え、正解やったー！
Ah, you got it! Yay, correct!
正解、タコさん！
Correct, Takosan!
動きすぎたのだよね、うん、動画ではタコさんなんだろ。
You moved too much, right? Yeah, in the video it's Takosan.
にょきにょきしてるのだから、簡単なんだろ！
Since it's squirming around, it must be easy!
ってことでまして、えー、2問目はなんだこれ？えー、みんなよく見てるのだよ。
And so, um, what is the second question? Everyone, look closely.
うわー！、え、ちょっと待って！、え？
Whoa! Eh, wait a minute! Eh?
えー…
Uhm...
ああ、やられた…
Ah, I got beaten...
当たったー！
Got it!
誰もいないのだな？なんでまた当たったのだな？
Is no one here? Why did you get it right again?
これは、ほら、みんな、ほら…
This is, look, everyone, look...
うわ、ぶ、ブブってなっちゃったのだな！
Whoa, it buzzed wrong!
もう、正解は、ルーナの一番苦手なもの、それは…
So, the correct answer is Luna's least favorite thing, which is...
あの、サメちゃんが、生きてるのか死んでるのかわからない状態で、地面に落ちてる状態の、時、あれ、あれ、あのサメちゃんがルーナ苦手なのだな、あれだったのだな！
Uhm, when Same-chan is lying on the ground not knowing if she's alive or dead, that state... that Same-chan is what Luna dislikes, that was it!
分かるでしょ！、え、え、えって、こっちらと、ちらっと見て…、い、い、ちゅ、ちゅ、ちゅ、違うな、なのだな！
You know, right!? Eh, eh, eh, looking over here, glancing... w-w-w-wait, that's wrong!
それが、それが答えだったのだよ、みんな、まだまだなのだね！
That, that was the answer, everyone, you still have a long way to go!
サメちゃんは、な…
Same-chan...
なんなのら…
What is this...
次は最後の
Next is the final
お題、こちらの方からいただきましたぁ！
prompt, given to us by this senior here!
あちゃん！
Ah-chan!
じゃこのちゃん何なのだろうこの問題？
So what could this problem be?
難しすぎて耳ドノラ！
It's so hard, I'm baffled!
みんなこれもう、もうどんなの？このね、あのパンダマームじゃなくて
Everyone, what kind of... not panda mime,
演技での、みんなちゃんとう見破ってほしいの！いくのらよ！
but acting! I want you all to see right through it! Here we go!
あ！
Ah!
わかったのら！
I get it!
あ、惜しい！惜しいのらけど嘘！あ、惜しいのら、
Ah, so close! So close, but no! Ah, so close,
それをもの、最後まで、最後までこの…
but you gotta keep going right to the very end...
あー！
Ah!
えへへ！
Ehehe!
あ、正解だったのら？
Oh, was that correct?
みんなありがちょーなのら！
Thank you so much, everyone!
正解はラーメンの湯切りをしていたら中に入っていた眼鏡が飛んでいってしまった店主なのら！
The answer was: A ramen chef whose glasses flew off while straining noodles!
なんなのらこれ？ルナの演技力でさ、みんな当てられたのならね、さすんなのら！
What is this? If everyone could guess it from Luna's acting, you guys are amazing!
ルナ上手だったのらね。
Luna was so good at it.
じゃ、次回して、このちゃんの2番目の問題は…
Now, moving on to the next one, the second problem is...
うーん、あ、これ簡単なのらね！
Hmm, ah, this one's easy!
いくのらよ！
Here we go!
惜しい！うん！
So close! Yeah!
最後まで、最後までみんな…！最後まで、最後まで！
To the very end, everyone...! To the very end!
あ、いた！正解！正解ちゅー！
Ah, you got it! Correct! Correct!
なーんと正解は、夏にスイカの種を飛ばす人なのら！
The correct answer was: Someone spitting watermelon seeds in summer!
もう単体じゃなのらね、問題がもう…どう説明したらいいのら？
It's not just a simple thing anymore, the question is... how should I explain it?
ま、それをねルナはね、見事にね表現してしまったのらね！
Well, Luna expressed it so splendidly!
どうなのら？え、ルナ、ちゃんと正解したのら？
How is that? Eh, did Luna guess it right?
ルナもしや正解してしまったのら？しゅごいのらー！
Could Luna have guessed it right? That's amazing!
みんながね当ててくれた
Thanks to everyone guessing it,
おかげ…ま、あとはルナの演技力なのらなのかな？
well, I guess it's thanks to Luna's acting skills too?
うますぎたのらね！
She was too good at it!
合格なのらね！これでルナは次のケーキが食べれるのら！
I passed! Now Luna gets to eat the next cake!
わあーい！
Yay!
ちょっとケーキ食べる前に、少し運動取り入れてもいいなら！
Before eating cake, maybe I should do a little exercise!
あ、ケーキ！ついに用意してくれたのらね！
Ah, cake! You finally prepared it for me!
こっちのね、ちょっとお疲れのら…
Over here, I'm a bit tired...
あ、ケーキ、すじに、
Ah, the cake, al-
あ、ケーキ！すでに用意してくれたのらね！ありがとうなのら！
Ah, cake! You already prepared it! Thank you so much!
じゃ、ケーキ食べるのら！おら、さい！おら！えい！
Now, time to eat cake! Here we go! Take this! Hah!
あー！もぐもぐもぐもぐもぐ…うまいのは！
Ah! Nom nom nom nom... So delicious!
ケーキはなんこ食べてもうまいのは！
Cake is delicious no matter how many you eat!
あれ、あれ、すず、な、なんなの？なんか言い出そうにしてるけど、どうしたの？あ？
Huh? What's this? You're trying to say something, what's wrong? Huh?
姫様！ケーキ食べ過ぎずぞ！！ちょっと運動をしたほうが良いのでは？
Princess! You're eating too much cake!! Shouldn't you exercise a bit?
え？どういうことなの？え、どういうこと？
Eh? What do you mean? Eh, what's that?
え、ルナ今日誕生日だから…！け、け、け、ケーキ！
Eh, today is Luna's birthday...! Ca- ca- ca- cake!
ケーキケーキ！あー！ケーキ食べて応援してやるのらね！運動って…え？なになに？
Cake, cake! Ah! Eating cake to support me! Exercise... Eh? What, what?
あ、オッケー！お菓子が！あー！お菓子が！あー！ちょっと！
Ah, okay! Snacks are! Ah! Snacks are! Ah! Wait!
待って！なんなのら！あー！
Wait! What is this! Ah!
はあ...
Haa...
ああね！ああね！ああ！ああね、ほら！
Ah, hey! Ah, hey! Ah! Ah, hey, look!
ああね！ほら！ああね！ふう...
Ah, hey! Look! Ah, hey! Phew...
ま、まさかそんな...な、な、なんと...！
No... way... C-Could it really be...!
なんじゃこの世界は！
What is this world?!
いたい！な、な、な、な、なんと...！
It hurts! Th-Th-Th-Th-This can't be...!
まじで何も見えないのだけど。え、放送事故じゃないのこれ？
Seriously, I can't see anything. Wait, isn't this a broadcast accident?
え、なんな、な、な、な、な、なんと...！うっ、うっ、運動って、し、し、食後の運動よくないと思うのだけど、な、なんと...！
Wh-What, wh-wh-wh-wh-what...?! Ugh, ugh, exercise, I-I-I think exercising right after eating isn't good, but wh-what...!
空気で和ましてるの...！
You're trying to break the tension with air...!
なんかへんな、へんなところとボタンが足されたらなんのなの...！
Why are there weird, weird places and buttons added...!
え、そ、おえ！おええええ！
Eh, w-whoa! Whoa-whoa-whoa!
まじだなのら！羊、やりてぇか！？やりてぇか！？やりてぇかっ！んなことあるなのら！
Seriously, nanora! Sheep, do you wanna do it?! Do you wanna do it?! Do you wanna do it?! As if that's a thing, nanora!
みんな...全部はいいのら。るな。リングフィットやるのらよ！
Everyone... It's all good, nanora. Luna. We're gonna play Ring Fit!
リングフィットやるのらよ！
We're gonna play Ring Fit!
あ、みて！これ、るなの、あの...輪っか！
Ah, look! This is Luna's, um... hoop!
たこ焼き輪っか！
Takoyaki hoop!
ま、これはね、るなね、リングフィットは何回もやってきとったからね。まあ、疲れることなくちょちょちょのちょでこなすためのらよ！
Well, as for this, Luna's played Ring Fit many times, so she can breeze right through it without getting tired, nanora!
じゃあ、まだね、まあ、えっと、普通のアドベンチャーではなく今回はね、お手軽のでこっちでやっていこうと思うのら。
Well, instead of the usual Adventure, this time we'll do the quick and easy ones here.
ちょっとね、あまりこれやったことないのだけど、結構きついらしいのよね。どれってやるのら？
I haven't done this much, but apparently it's pretty tough. Which one should I do?
これってやるのら？これちょっと見てもらうとわかるのだけど、データがやばいのよ。えーちゃんどんだけやったのらこれ。
Should I do this? If you look at this, you'll see the data is crazy. E-chan, how much did you do this?
フレンドがね、えーちゃんの記録しかないのよこれ。
My friends... the only records are E-chan's.
なんなのら？これ、どうにしようかな。
What is this? Hmm, what should I do?
まあ、えっとね、じゃあこのね、スト、ストイックにちょっと大胸筋を鍛えたいと思うのらよ！えーちゃんの記録をね、頑張って抜かしたいと思うのら。みんな、見ててなのらね！いけるのらよ、殺生！
Well, then I want to train my pectorals stoically with this! I want to work hard and beat E-chan's record. Everyone, watch me, nanora! I can do it, merciless!
はあ！
Ha!
戻して！
Bring it back!
あ、余裕なのだ！
Ah, this is a breeze!
戻して！
Bring it back!
いいよ！戻して！
Good! Bring it back!
はあ！
Ha!
戻して！
Bring it back!
はあ！
Ha!
戻して！
Bring it back!
あ、余裕なのだ！
Ah, this is a breeze!
あ、ちょっと待って！
Ah, wait a minute!
うそら！
No way!
百回とかうそら！
A hundred times, no way!
戻して！
Bring it back!
体が負けてたなのだ！
My body was losing!
ちょっと待って手痛いのら！
Wait a minute, my hands hurt, nanora!
いたい！え、な、え、いたいいたい！いたい！やばい！いたい！いたい！
It hurts! Eh, w-eh, it hurts so much! It hurts! Oh no! It hurts! It hurts!
いたい！てが、いたい！
It hurts! My hands hurt!
いたい！うに！
It hurts! U-ni!
いたい！ちょっと待って！足がだんだんなくなってきたのら！
It hurts! Wait a minute! My legs are gradually disappearing, nanora!
え、てくしゃんもう無理なのら！
Eh, Te-kushan, I can't do this anymore, nanora!
むりや…おに、もうむり…
I can't... Demon mode, I can't anymore...
えーちゃんは化け物なのだ
E-chan is a monster...
これは記録しな…どうこなの…るなのこの記録はまずいのだ…残すしかないのかなのだ…
Should I save this record...? What is this... Luna's record is terrible. I guess I have to not save it...
みんなもうるなちゃん過酷じゃなのだ
Everyone, this is too harsh for Luna-chan.
ストイック三角筋…あぁ、こんなの最初から飛ばしすぎはよくないから、ミニゲームにするのだな
Stoic Deltoids... Ah, going too hard from the start isn't good, so I'll do a minigame instead.
あ、ちょっと待って…
Ah, wait a second...
あ、背中だくたくなのだ…あ、待って、ミニゲームじゃないじゃない
Ah, my back is all stiff... Ah, wait, this isn't a minigame!
どうなんじゃよ…おー
What's this... Oh—
あ、るなね、ちょっと今腕を負傷してしまったから、あ、残すしかないのだね
Ah, Luna, well, I just injured my arm a bit, so... ah, I guess I have to not save it.
内ももライダー…内ももでリングコンを挟んで上手に操縦してあげよう。お、これはね、記録残してあるのだね。じゃ、これでやろうのだ
Thigh Rider... Let's steer skillfully by squeezing the Ring-Con between our thighs. Oh, this one already has a record saved. Well, let's do this one.
え、これ何にするのだな
Um, which one should I pick?
いす、あ、いす座るのだね。いす座るのだ、ちょっと、るな座るのだね。あ、浅く座って背筋を伸ばして
Chair... Ah, sitting on a chair. Sitting on a chair, wait, Luna is sitting. Sit forward and straighten your back.
いや、やだ、るなのだおまる…みんなみんな、やだ！るなの、おまる…え、背筋を伸ばして、太ももでリングコンを挟んで押し込む
No, no, Luna's potty... Everyone, no! Luna's potty... Ugh, straighten your back, squeeze the Ring-Con between your thighs and push in.
痛い！え、挟んだ挟んだ！痛い！痛い、太もも痛い！
It hurts! Hey, I squeezed it! It hurts! It hurts, my thighs hurt!
うわあ！
Uwaah!
え、動かない！痛い！痛い！
Eh, it won't move! It hurts! It hurts!
え、まだ動かない！痛い！痛い！痛い！
Eh, still not moving! It hurts! It hurts! It hurts!
全然動かない！ちょっと待って！うわあ！動かないからきろく…
It's not moving at all! Wait a second! Uwaah! Because it won't move, my record...
弱く、弱くにする！弱く…あ、これで、太ももが限界きてる…
Make it weaker, weaker! Weaker... Ah, with this, my thighs are reaching their limit...
あ、痛い！違う！
Ah, it hurts! No!
あ、これじゃん！これじゃん！あ、あ、いける！いける！
Ah, this is it! This is it! Ah, ah, I can do it! I can do it!
あ、痛い！痛い！痛い！みんな痛いのだ！あーー！
Ah, it hurts! It hurts! It hurts! Everyone, it hurts! Aaah!
ジャンプどうやってするの！あーー！
How do you jump?! Aaah!
ふっか…あーー！
Fucca... Aaah!
どうするの！あ、しゃがまな…しゃがんで、ジャンプ！
What do I do! Ah, squat... squat and jump!
ジャンプ！あーー！
Jump! Aaah!
あ、なんでダブジなるの！ダブジして、ジャンプ、ジャンプ！
Ah, why is it doubling? Double and jump, jump!
あ、できたできた！コーナー！あ、できたできた！あ、ちょっと待って！あ、あ、あ、ちょっと！
Ah, I did it, I did it! Corner! Ah, I did it, I did it! Ah, wait a second! Ah, ah, ah, wait!
あーー！あーー！あーー！あーー！
Aaah! Aaah! Aaah! Aaah!
あ、ちょっとちょっと、どうにかなってきた！あーー！あーー！あーー！
Ah, wait a second, I'm getting the hang of it! Aaah! Aaah! Aaah!
こうやって、ちゃんとこうやって飛ばないと…おーー！飛んでる飛んでる！
If you don't jump like this properly... Ooh! I'm flying, I'm flying!
見て！王子飛んでる！え、何これ？
Look! The prince is flying! Eh, what is this?
え？あ、終わった！
Eh? Ah, it's over!
何なのだ？…え？500点？何なのだこれ？何なのだこれ…どういうことなのだ？
What is this...? Eh? 500 points? What is this? What is this... What does this mean?
どういうことなのだ？500…でもるながんばったのだよ。
What does this mean? 500... But Luna did her best.
何なのだ？えーちゃん7300て何なのこれ。ふざけんな、ふざけんななのだ！
What is this? E-chan got 7300, what is that? Are you kidding me, stop messing around!
あー
Ah...
あ、ちょっと想像よりもきつい
Ah, this is way tougher than I imagined.
なんになの？
What is this?
ちょっと、思ったよりもミニゲームが全然ミニじゃないのになの！
Wait, these minigames are way bigger than I thought!
きっと、きっとすげえのになの？なになの？
It must be, it must be amazing! What's going on?
どれにしよう？なんかもっと、るーなができるやつがいいのになのね。
Which one should I do? I want something Luna can actually do.
でも、ちょっとあまりにも、ちょっとかっこいいところ見せられないから。
But... I can't really show off a cool side here.
んー、ろくろ回し？あ、これやるのね？
Hmm, Pottery? Oh, I do this one?
やってるところ見せてやるのな。
I'll show you me doing it.
これはね、やるの。ろくろからおまかせなの。
I'll do this. I'll leave the pottery to auto.
ろくろのできあがりをこう…合わせるのな。
Aligning the finished pottery like this...
きつっ！
So tight!
えー、ろくろこ、このへん？このへん？
Um, pottery, around here? Around here?
あ、なんかへっこみすぎたような…
Ah, it feels like I indented it too much...
いいんだななの！
That's fine!
いいんだななの！いいんだななの！
That's fine! That's fine!
あー、凹みすぎたか。
Ah, did I indent too much?
足が痛い！足が…うっ、ちょっと、あーっ！
My legs hurt! My legs... Ugh, wait, ahh!
きつい！あーっ、はっ、はっ！
It's tough! Ah, hah, hah!
何が違うのな？もう本物そっくりじゃないのなこれ。
What's different? Isn't this an exact replica?
何が違うのな？おっ、そっくりじゃん！
What's different? Oh, it's identical!
そっか、完成、完成なのな！
I see, it's finished, it's done!
完成なのだー！
It's complete!
100点じゃないのな、これわ！
This isn't 100 points!
これバケてんだろななの、なんなのな？
Is this bugged, what is this?
なんなのな？
What is this?
なんだみんなのこの、この点数はなんなのな？
What are everyone's scores here?
なんなのな？うんでるのななの。
What is this? She's doing great.
ちょっと、えーちゃんのと、えーちゃんやめて！もうるーながしょぼく見えてしまうのな！
Wait, A-chan's... A-chan, stop! It makes Luna look so lame!
みんなのデータがあるせいで、るーなの凄さが分からなくなっている。
Because of everyone's data, Luna's greatness is getting lost.
みんなのデータ消して、消してくんないと、るーなが全然すごく見えなかっちゃうのな。
If you don't delete everyone's data, Luna won't look amazing at all.
みんな、な、みんなるーな頑張ってるのだから、みんなこれ本当大変なのだからね。
Everyone, well, everyone, Luna is working hard, so this is really tough, you know.
えーちゃんすごいのとか思って、見ながら、なのだって、頑張ってるのだから。
Thinking A-chan is amazing, while watching... because she's working hard.
あ、わかった！えーちゃんがやってないやつやればいいんじゃないのな？
Ah, I know! Shouldn't I just do one A-chan hasn't done?
あ、これやってないのな！
Ah, she hasn't done this one!
よし、るーな1位取るのだな。るーなこれで1位取るから！
Alright, Luna's gonna take 1st place. Luna's taking 1st place with this!
ばんざいゲット！はい。
Banzai Get! Yes.
あ、これなんか、あれ、半身にやった気がする。
Ah, this feels like I did it with one side before.
あ、これ半身にやったのな、るー知ってたのな。
Ah, I did this with one side, Luna knew that.
いけ、いけ！おっけー！
Go, go! Okay!
これはるーな1位取れちゃうのなね。おっけー、簡単なのだな！
Luna can take 1st place with this. Okay, it's easy!
簡単なのだな。はい！
It's easy. Yes!
よゆうなのだね、ふっ、はい！
Piece of cake, huh. Fu-, yes!
あ、ちょっとラグがある。ふっ、うっ！
Ah, there's a bit of lag. Fu-, ugh!
はい！うっ、うっ、うっ、あ、よいしょ！
Yes! Ugh, ugh, ugh, ah, heave-ho!
ちょっと早めにやらないと
I need to do it a bit earlier...
あ、ズレた
Ah, it slipped.
ズレる、く、く、く、くっ
It's slipping—ugh, ugh!
ちょっと手が、そのその、いしょ
My hands are... wait, wait, hup!
あ、取れた
Ah, I got it.
あ、終わった
Ah, it's over.
みんな見てー！みんな見てー！
Everyone look! Everyone look!
えー、えっと、取った
Um, let's see, I got it.
これ、ルナね、ハイパー1位を取れたから、記録させてもらうのだ
Since Luna got 1st place in Hyper, I'm going to save my record.
はずじゃなくて、ランクＡ！
It's not a miss, Rank A!
これだね、これでみんなの記録が見れるんだけど、ルナのなのだ、ここにね、おんで、あ、これね、ここにちょっと保存させてもらうのだ
With this, you can see everyone's records. Luna's here... I'll save it right here!
やった、1位ー！
Yay, 1st place!
1位ー！やったのだー！
1st place! Yay!
じゃあちょっと休むのだ
Now I'll take a little break.
ちょっと、何でもいいのなら
Wait, if anything is fine...
ちょっと休憩と
Take a little break...
みんなもね、運動して大変だと思うから、休憩していいのだから。
Everyone must be having a hard time exercising too, so it's okay to take a break.
あ、みんなさ、どんなトレーニングやってくれてるのだろ？
Hey everyone, what kind of training are you doing?
あ、ルナ体力あるから、余裕なのだけどね。
Well, Luna has stamina, so it's a breeze though.
余裕待ってるから、余裕なのだけどね。
I'm waiting with room to spare, so it's easy for me.
じゃあ次、次もこれやりたいのだよね。ルナやったことあるやつのほうが
Next, I want to do this one too. The ones Luna has done before are better...
あ、そしてデータがないやつのほうがルナ1位取れるから。来た！
Ah, and the ones without data are better so Luna can take 1st place. Here it comes!
あれ、ここコインランさっきやったやつ？あ、さっきの、あ、違う。
Huh, is this Coin Run the one I just did? Ah, the last one... oh wait, no.
バンザイじゃない！走るやつやん！
It's not Banzai! It's the running one!
これ、やるか。これでまたね、1位の記録を残したいと思うのだ。
Let's do this one. I want to leave a 1st-place record with this too.
はい。初級。
Okay. Beginner.
ランって言ってるから、これ走るんじゃねえのだ、もしかして。
It says "Run", so maybe we're not supposed to run?
走るけ……、ルナの、2回目！
Run ke... Luna's second time!
ちょっとやめていいの？
Can I stop for a bit?
ちょっと甘えたくなってきた。
I'm starting to want to slack off.
おらぁ、るなななの
Heyaa, Runanana's...
あ、コインと、走りすぎた！走りすぎた！
Ah, coins, I ran too much! Ran too much!
まずい、難しい。
Oh no, it's hard.
いい感じ。
Feels good.
うわ、いる！
Whoa, they're here!
ああ、下がって下がって下がって！
Ah, back up, back up, back up!
え、下がって！あ、下がって！ここらの、はい！
Eh, back up! Ah, back up! Around here, right!
あらららら、あららららら！
Oh my goodness!
息すぎそ……。おらあ！
I'm running out of breath... Take this!
はじまるー！はじまるー！
Starting! Starting!
いきのこれ！
Survive!
終わるな！
Don't end!
◆リングコンを下に向けて！
Point the Ring-Con downward!
ちょっと待って！そんなの無理！
Wait a second! That's impossible!
あや、落ちて…
Oh, watch out...
あい、ジャンプ！ジャンプ！ジャンプ！
Jump! Jump! Jump!
またー！うそ、なんだんだ！
Again?! No way, what is this?!
もって… もう無理！
I can't take it... I'm done!
◆リングコンを下に向けて！
Point the Ring-Con downward!
おこられるー！
I'm gonna get scolded!
Finish
今回の結果
Result
一、二、とっ、とっ、七、一、二、とっ…
One, two, hop, hop, seven, one, two, hop...
たすけてぇよー…
Somebody help me...
あー、またまっすぐなんだー…
Ah, straight ahead again...
はあ、これさー、みんな疲れた演技なんだよ、これ。
Whew, y'know, this is all just an acting tired bit, y'know.
ちょっと足が… あー、足がガクガクする…
My legs... Ah, my legs are shaking...
ちょっとみんな… ちょっとたーま、はぁたーま…
Everyone... Just a mome— hah, a mome—...
まあ、もちろんこれをいれば、演技できまーたんなのだよ。
Well, of course if I do this, it's totally acting, y'know.
足が痛い！足痛いからさー、よゆうなんだよ、ほらほらほらほら！
My legs hurt! My legs hurt so much, so I've got this totally easy, see, see, see, see!
みんな！ルナと遊んでね、運動してね、疲れたと思うのだよ。
Everyone! Playing with Luna, exercising, you must be tired.
疲れたみんなのためにね、ルナ…
For everyone who's tired, Luna...
このあとはね、みんなにね、癒やしを与えようと思っているのだよ。
Afterwards, y'know, I'm thinking of giving everyone some healing.
でもその前に、息を… ちょっとのーさしてもらえたらなのね。
But before that, letting me catch my breath... I'd appreciate it, y'know.
心臓バクバク言ってるけど、大丈夫なのだよ。
My heart is pounding like crazy, but I'm totally fine.
このあとに、息を… ととのえないとね、難しいことがあるからね。
After this, I gotta... catch my breath, 'cause there's some tricky stuff coming up.
みんな、ルナちょっと元気だから、ルナ元気だからね、みんな！
Everyone, Luna is a little energetic, Luna is full of energy, y'know, everyone!
今ちょっときょもってるとか思わないでほしいのな。
I hope you don't think I'm acting weird right now or anything.
おっ、これは？
Oh, what is this?
これは、みんな、なんだ？
What is this, everyone, what?
これはなんだろう？ あららら？
I wonder what this is? Oh my?
おろろろろろろろろろろ！
Whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa!
みんな！きっとね、リングフィットでね、みんな疲れたと思うから、ルナがね、ピアノでね、みんなのことをね、癒やしてあげようと思うなら。
Everyone! I'm sure you're all tired from Ring Fit, so Luna's gonna heal you all with piano playing, if I think about it.
間違えちゃうかもしれないけど、みんな…
I might make mistakes, but everyone...
ルナのピアノの演奏をね、聞いてくれたら、うれしいなら。
I'd be so happy if you'd listen to Luna's piano performance.
ね、みんな！ルナね、いつもピアノの練習とかしているの！
Right, everyone! Luna's always practicing piano, y'know!
みんなの 今日3Dでね
Today in 3D,
みんなの前で お披露目をしようと思うなら
if I'm going to debut it in front of everyone,
うん…ふふっ
Yeah... hehe.
息切れもしたなか大丈夫なのだ 呼吸を止めて聴かせて貰うなら
I'm a bit out of breath, but it'll be okay. If you hold your breath and listen,
みんなにね ルナのピアノ聴いて貰ってね 癒されて貰えたら
I hope you all listen to Luna's piano and feel relaxed and healed.
な 曲は パッヘルベルのカノン
So, the song is Pachelbel's Canon.
いくのだよ 間違えちゃうかもしれないのだよ 間違えちゃったらごめんねなのだね
Here I go. I might make a mistake, so please forgive me if I do!
あと途中 あの 骨組みで止まるけど 気にしないで最後まで聴いてくれたら嬉しいのだ
Also, it might pause a bit in the middle, but please don't mind and listen to the end!
では 聴かせて頂くのだ
Well then, please enjoy listening.
あ 間違えちゃった
Ah, I made a mistake.
にゃーい、ふふっ
Nya-i! Fufu~
みんなあ、どうだったのら？
Everyone, how was it?
今日、間違いを噛んじゃったのら
Today, I stumbled over my mistakes...
みんな聴いてくれて、ありがとう！
Thank you everyone for listening!
まぁ、ちょっと指外しちゃったのら
Well, I slipped up a bit with my fingers...
おわあ！
Whoa!
やっぱ間違えちゃったけど
I still made a mistake though...
やっぱ間違えちゃったけど、どうだったのら？
I still made a mistake, but how was it?
ありがとう、みんな！
Thank you, everyone!
手がブルブルしちゃった、はずかちい！でも無事弾けてよかったの！
My hands were shaking, how embarrassing! But I'm glad I played it safely!
そうね、このね、ぷりりりね、ピアノがね、ちゃんとこう、弾いてるところをね、みんなに見せることができてね、すごい嬉しいのらよ。
Being able to show everyone where I played this piano properly makes me so happy.
え、ありがとう！ピアノさんで、ありがとう！
Eh, thank you! Piano-san, thank you!
ね、今日はね、誕生日だからね、ちょっと頑張ったのら！みんなありがとう！
You know, today is my birthday, so I worked hard! Thank you everyone!
ということでね、あの、この後ね、みんなにね、ランチのね、お知らせがあります！
And so, um, after this, everyone, I have an announcement about lunch!
こちらです！姫森ルナ誕生日記念ボイス2020、10月10日、今日、販売開始されております！
Here it is! The Himemori Luna Birthday Voice 2020 is on sale starting today, October 10th!
こちらはセット販売で、記念ボイスと記念グッズが全部セットになった、特典で直筆サイン入りポストカードとポストカード特典付きです！
This is a set sale containing all commemorative voice clips and goods, including a bonus postcard with a handwritten autograph!
ボイス付きいいのら！あとね、見て、イラスト見てほしいのら！ういママんなのら！
With voice! Also, look, I want you to see the illustration! It's by Ui-mama!
かわいいのら、ルナ！ういママのね、お誕生日のピザを食べてるのが一緒になってるからなのら！
Cute, Luna! It's because we're shown eating birthday pizza together by Ui-mama!
見て、かわいい！かわいい！イラストポストカード付き、数量限定セットにはね、ルナの直筆サイン入りのポストカードがついてくるのら！
Look, cute! Cute! The limited quantity set comes with a postcard featuring Luna's handwritten autograph!
受注生産、複製サイン入りポストカード特典付き全部セットにはね、この、お、見えるのら？あのね、きんぴかの複製サイン入りのポストカードもね、ついてくるのら！
The made-to-order set with duplicated autograph postcard bonus includes this... can you see it? That gold-foiled, duplicated autograph postcard as well!
ぜひね、みんな、聴いてみて！タペストリーをお部屋に飾ってほしいのら！
Please everyone, give it a listen! I want you to hang the tapestry in your room!
えへ、ルナめっちゃかわいいのらよね。同じポーズで寝ている？
Ehe, Luna is super cute, right? Sleeping in the same pose?
かわいい！ありがとう！
So cute! Thank you!
みんなね ぜひぜひ購入してみたい ほしいなら
Everyone, please definitely go buy it if you want it!
概要欄にね リンクがね もう貼ってあるので そっからぴょーんって飛んでね
The link is already posted in the description box, so just hop right over!
もう販売開始されてるから ぜひ聞いてみてねだな！
Sales have already started, so please be sure to listen!
お誕生日記念だから みんな聞いてね ののボイスいっぱい録音したから ぜひぜひ聞いてみてほしいのだな！
It's for my birthday, so everyone listen! I recorded lots of Luna voices, so please definitely check them out!
なんかね もうすごいなんかす おー いろいろ入ってるから いろんな種類のボイスが入ってるから聞いてほしいのだな！
There are all sorts of things included, with many different types of voice lines, so I want you to listen!
では 最後にね
Now, lastly...
みんな今日ね ののの誕生日会に来てくれて本当にありがとうなのだな！ののがやりたいこと今日いっぱいできて本当に幸せなのだな！
Thank you all so much for coming to Luna's birthday party today! I'm so happy I got to do everything I wanted!
みんなからもねお祝いしてもらえてのの本当に嬉しい！みんな本当ありがとうなのだな！
I'm so happy to receive everyone's celebrations! Thank you all so much!
最後にね 歌をね 一曲歌っておわ 歌ってセットしてもらって終わりにしようと思うのだな！
Lastly, I'm thinking of having a song set up to close things out!
みんなありがとう！
Thank you everyone!
眠れない 夜きみのせいだよ
I can't sleep tonight, this is all your fault.
さっき 別れた ばかりなのに
Even though it was only moments since we said goodbye,
耳たぶが for you 燃えている for you
My ears are burning red for you.
やった やった やったよ ohh
Alright! Oh yeah, I did it! Ohh~
はじめての チュー 君と チュー
My first kiss was a kiss from you.
I will give you all my love
なぜか 優しい 気持ちが いっぱい
Funny enough, I'm so full of these gentle feelings.
はじめての チュー 君と チュー
My first kiss was a kiss from you.
I will give you all my love
涙が 出いちゃう 男の くせに
Though I'm a guy, my tears are starting to run down.
Be in love with you
デートコースは もう 決めたんだ
I've already set the plans for our date.
明日(あした)の 夢が ふくらんでくる
My dreams of tomorrow have gotten bigger.
この愛を to you いつでも to you
This love to you, will always be to you.
きっと きっと きっとさ ohh
I'm positive! Absolutely! For certain! Ohh~
はじめての チュー 君と チュー
My first kiss was a kiss from you.
I will give you all my love
なぜか 優しい 気持ちが いっぱい
Funny enough, I'm so full of these gentle feelings.
はじめての チュー 君と チュー
My first kiss was a kiss from you.
I will give you all my love
涙が 出いちゃう 男の くせに
Though I'm a guy, my tears are starting to run down.
Be in love with you
はじめての チュー 君と チュー
My first kiss was a kiss from you.
I will give you all my love
なぜか 優しい 気持ちが いっぱい
Funny enough, I'm so full of these gentle feelings.
はじめての チュー 君と チュー
My first kiss was a kiss from you.
I will give you all my love
涙が 出いちゃう 男の くせに
Though I'm a guy, my tears are starting to run down.
Be in love with you
Loving you
3D 誕生日
3D Birthday
Loving you
3D 誕生日
3D Birthday